摩妮卡  厨房有哪些东西是我的
Monica, which of all of this kitchen stuff is mine?
这个开罐器
This bottle opener.
还有呢  还有上面的磁铁
And...? And it's a magnet.
你看
Look at that.
多巧啊  你要搬来跟我住
How weird is that? You know, you're moving in with me...
而我就缺一个开罐器
...and you have the one thing I don't have. Ha, ha.
彷佛是你让我变得完整
It's like, in a way, you complete me. Huh?
我是说厨房  什么
Kitchen. What?
你让我的厨房变得完整   室友
You complete me kitchen, matey.
罗斯  我知道你在想什么  什么
Ross, I know what you're thinking. What?
她搬去跟你住之后
That she's gonna move in with you...
或许会爱上你
...and then maybe fall in love with you, and then...
等她发现你们还有婚姻关系  就会很高兴
...when she finds out you're already married, oh, she'll be happy.
你真的很悲哀
You know? You're just-You're very sad.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
我终于知道了  你爱上瑞秋了
I see what this is. You are in love with Rachel.
什么  没错  这就对了
What? Of course. It all adds up.
你迷恋她
I mean, you're obsessed with her. It's always:
"罗斯  瑞秋的事怎么办"
"Ross, what are you gonna do about Rachel?
"罗斯  你为何要跟瑞秋住"
Ross, why are you moving in with Rachel?
"你何时要承认没办注销"
When are you gonna confess your secret marriage to Rachel?"
你想要她  乱讲
You want her. No!
电话救了你一命
Uh-oh. Saved by the bell.
你好
Hello.
瑞秋  这对烛台不是我的吗
Hey, Rach. Aren't these Candlesticks mine?
不   那是我买的
No, no, I bought those.
对喔   我忘了  对
Oh, right. I forgot. Yeah.
忘了你是个骗子
That you're a liar.
不会  太好了  我星期一过去  再次谢谢你
No, no, that's great. I'll be there Monday. And thank you again.
好的
0Kay.
是纽约大学   古生物学的
Um, that was the head of the paleontology department...
系…主…任
...at NYU.
他…说…什么
Wow. What did he say?
记得我那篇沉积速率论文吗
Uh, remember that paper I had published last year on sediment flow rate?
他们很喜欢  有谁会不喜欢
Well, they loved it. Well, who wouldn't?
就是嘛
I know!
总之   他们要聘我当客座教授
Anyway, they asked me to be a guest lecturer.
是暂时的  但表现好就可能转任正职
I mean, it's temporary, but if they like me, it could lead to a full-time job.
标在信箱上可帅了  盖勒教授
How great would that look on the mailbox, huh? Professor Geller.
是啊  教授与夫人
Yeah. Professor and Mrs.
与夫人
And Mrs.?
对  你和罗斯还是夫妻
Oh, yeah, you know, you and Ross are still married.
什么
What?
开玩笑的啦
Just kidding.
天啊
Oh, God.
救了你的狗命
Saved your ass.
老友记  第六季  第4集  装腔作调
Friends  S06E04  The One Where Joey Loses His Insurance
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
嘿  嗨
Hey. Hi.
嘿   怎么了
Hey. What's the matter?
嗯
Well, ahem.
我不是在看巫师（通灵的或有特异功能）吗   是啊
You know that psychic I see? Yeah?
她说我这个星期会死
She told me that I'm gonna die this week...
所以我有点沮丧
...so I'm kind of bummed about that.
什么  对   我知道你们不太懂通灵术
What? I know you don't know about readings...
但这应该算是最糟糕的预言了
...but that one is pretty much the worst one you can get.
菲比   这也太夸张了
Phoebe, that's crazy.
她居然咒你死
I can't believe she'd say that to you?
亲爱的  你不会相信吧
Yeah, honey, you don't believe her, do you?
我不知道  她预言过我会生三胞胎
I don't know. She, you know, said that I'd have triplets...
但她也说会有一个黑宝宝
...but she also said one of them would be black.
纯属好奇啊   她有提到死法吗
Just out of curiosity, did she tell you how you were gonna go?
没有   她到最后才告诉我
No, because she didn't tell me I was gonna die till the end of the session.
我不想再跟她多耗一小时了
And I was not gonna waste a whole other hour there.
我只剩下一星期了
I mean, I've only got a week left, you know?
我得开始享受人生了
I've really gotta start living now.
（汽车与驾驶）
大家好  嗨
Hey, everyone. Oh, hi.
嘿   我今天第一次上课
Hey. Hey. Well, today's my first lecture...
想找你们演练一下  可以吗
...and I kind of wanted to try it out on you guys. Do you mind?
好啊   没问题
No, that'd be great.
好吧
0Kay.
沉积速率有三个主要理论
"There are three primary theories concerning sediment flow rate.
每一个还可以细分为两个
Each of these theories can be further subcategorized into two"
我就是这样死的
Oh, this is it. This is what's gonna kill me.
类别  第一个是
"Subcategories. The first of these subcategories is"
罗斯
Um, Ross? Heh.
你那张纸上有裸女吗
Are there, uh, naked chicks on that piece of paper?
没有  怎么了
No. Why?
我没见过纸上没有裸女
Well, I just never seen a guy stare so hard at paper...
男人还会死盯着看
...that didn't have naked chicks on it.
好  好
Oh, okay. Okay.
沉积速率
"There are three primary theories...
有三个主要理论
...concerning sediment flow rate.
每一个还可以
Each of these theories...
细分为两个
...can be further subcategorized into--"
不如以笑话来开场
Why don't you open with a joke?
以笑话开场   那是大学啊   不是喜剧俱乐部
Open with a joke? It's a university, not a comedy club.
等一下  且慢
Wait a minute, hold the phone.
是咯咯窃笑大学吗
You're not talking about Chuckles University?
好
0Kay.
开玩笑的啦
Ohh! We’re kidding! Come on, we're kidding.
你知道怎么搞才会比较有趣吗
hey you know what might make it less boring?
谢谢你
Thank you.
运用影像辅助
Some, um-Some visual aids.
你知道  哪种影像辅助最好吗
Oh, oh! You know what's a good visual aid?
别跟我说裸女
Please don't say naked chicks.
为什么不行啊
Why not?
我真不知道干嘛要找你们商量
I don't even know why I bothered to even talk to you guys about it.
我自己解决   不必用裸女
You know, I'm just gonna do it on my own, with no naked chicks.
我十九岁之前就是那样
That's the way I did it till I was 19.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey
有什么好消息吗
Any good mail?
有  演员工会寄信给你
Yes, you got something from the Screen Actors Guild.
可能是重播费  你帮我拆一下  我
Ooh, it's probably a residual check. Hey, can you open it? I got...
"保险中止"   太奇怪了
"Benefits lapsed." Hmm. That's weird.
我不记得演过这部片子
I don't remember being in a movie called Benefits Lapsed.
这不是支票
Okay, it's not a check.
信上说由于你去年工作的不够
They're saying your health insurance expired because...
你的医疗保险过期了   我看看
...you didn't work enough last year. Let me see that.
好
All right.
不会吧
Oh, I can't believe this.
好烂喔
This sucks.
有保险时   我可以被车撞
When I had insurance, I could get hit by a bus...
或是被火烧
...or catch on fire, you know?
我都无所谓   现在却得小心了
And it wouldn't matter. Now I gotta be careful?
真可惜   被火烧这种事
I'm sorry, man. There's never a good time to have to...
停了总是不好
...stop catching on fire.
好吧
All right, well...
我得找工作了  我去见经纪人
...I guess I gotta go get a job. I'm gonna see my agent.
过马路要小心左右来车
Okay, make sure to look both ways before you cross the street.
"过马路要小心左右来车"
"Make sure to look both ways before you cross the street."
嘿   菲比  你还活着
Hey. Hey, Pheebs, you're still alive.
感觉如何
How are you feeling?
等死好累啊
It's so exhausting, waiting for death.
对了   你能不能
Oh, by the way, do you think you--
菲比  你干什么
Pheebs, what are you doing?
我在替你做心理   你没有以为我死了吗
I was preparing you for-Didn't you think I was dead?
我装得不像吗
Did that not come off?
真像啊  吓死我了  我还以为我们永别了
Oh, yeah, scared the hell out of me. I thought we'd lost you forever.
菲比  你要不要睡下  好  谢谢
Pheebs, you wanna lie down? Yeah, thanks.
对了  帮我一个忙
And listen, can you do me a favor?
两个小时后叫我
Could you just wake me up in a couple hours.
如果还能叫得醒的话
You know, if you can.
摩妮卡
Monica?
这是你摆回去的
Did you take these back?
不  不是  我很喜欢  就去买了一对
No-no, I-I just, I liked them so much that I went out and bought some for myself.
真的很好看  对吧
Oh, yeah, they're really great, aren't they?
我好喜欢
I love them. Yeah.
想耍诈
Nice try.
哈罗   课上得怎样
Hello. Hey, how'd the lecture go?
很顺利啊
It went great.
既不需要笑话   也不需要裸女
And I didn't need any jokes or naked chicks either.
太好了  抱歉之前没有好好帮忙
Oh, that's great. I'm sorry we weren't supportive before.
我就知道   教材充实最重要
I knew all I had to do was let the material speak for itself.
每个人都说  "你得表现的既风趣又性感"
Everyone's all, uh, "Ross, you have to be funny and sexy."
我证明他们错了
Well, I proved them wrong.
我现在就去告诉乔伊和钱德
And now I'm gonna pass the news on to Joey and Chandler.
说你既不风趣也不性感   没错
That you're not funny or sexy? That's right.
（伊斯特李奥纳德经纪公司）
伊斯特  听着  哇
Hey, Estelle, listen-Well, well, well.
乔伊崔比亚尼
Joey Tribbiani.
回来了  是吧
So you came back, huh?
每个人都以为走比较好  但最后
They think they can do better, but they all...
还不都爬回来求伊斯特
...come crawling back to Estelle.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我哪有离开  你一直是我的经纪人
I never left you. You've always been my agent.
是吗  是啊
Really? Yeah.
我没恶意   你别在意
Oh, well, no harm, no foul.
伊斯特  你得帮我找工作  我的医保没了
Look, Estelle, you gotta get me some work. I lost my health insurance.
好  首先我们得做伤害控制
All right, first thing we gotta do: damage control.
为什么  我觉得
Why? Well, I think, uh...
可能有人
...someone out there...
在到处中伤你
...may have been bad-mouthing you all over town.
不要脸
The bastard.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
明天伊斯特帮我排了一堆试镜
So Estelle lined up a bunch of auditions for me tomorrow.
我很快就能重新加入医保
And I'll have my health insurance back in no time.
太好了  但你现在应该去蹲马桶吧
That's great, but shouldn't you be on the toilet right now?
什么  你是怎么了
What? What's wrong with you?
没什么
Nothing.
我刚才举哑铃时  肚子突然一阵剧痛
Well, I got this blinding pain in my stomach when I was lifting weights before.
然后就昏倒了
And then I, uh, passed out...
而且一直就站不起来
...and, uh, I haven't been able to stand up since. Ha, ha.
不过  应该没什么
But I don't think it's anything serious.
这应该是疝气   你得去看医生
This sounds like a hernia. You have to-Go to the doctor.
我才不要
No way.
就算要去看医生
If I'm gonna go to the doctor for anything...
也是因为肚子这里突出来
...it's gonna be for this thing sticking out of my stomach.
那就是疝气
That's a hernia.
我为什么要恢复健身呢
Why'd I have to start working out again?
烂哑铃
Damn you, 15s.
（纽约大学）
我们提早到了  还要十五分钟才会开始
We're a little early. The lecture doesn't end for 15 minutes.
对   但我们可以偷偷溜进去看  是啊
Yeah, but we can sneak in and watch. Yeah. Good.
你看  是姊妹会的人
Oh, hey, look. There's some Kappa Kappa Deltas.
我以前也是会员  嘿  姊妹们
I was a Kappa. Hey, sisters.
哇  我们以前真是犯贱
Wow, we really are bitches.
好   瑞格比  从实验室
Right. So when Rigby got his samples...
取回样本后
...back from the laboratory...
有了惊人的发现
...he made a startling discovery.
他原以为那是火山物质   其实  是沉积物
What he believed to be igneous was, in fact, sedimentary.
他的惊愕
Imagine his consternation when--
糟糕
Oh, bloody hell.
你在搞什么啊
What the hell are you doing?
我很紧张
Look, I was nervous.
你们害我担心  我会很无聊的
You guys had me all worried I was gonna be boring.
我上了台   学生都盯着我看
I got up there and they were all, like, staring at me.
结果我一开口  满嘴的英国腔
I opened my mouth and this British accent just came out.
而且还很锉
Yeah, and not a very good one.
别再说了
Will you, please...?
盖勒博士   我是寇特拉斯曼
Dr. Geller? Kurt Rathman.
古生物学系教授
I'm a professor in the paleontology department here.
可以聊聊你的课吗
Do you have a moment to talk about your lecture?
抱歉了   我和我妹妹有约
I'm sorry, I've got plans with my sister.
摩妮卡 盖勒
Monica Geller.
是的  失陪一下
Right. Will you excuse us for one moment?
你干什么
What are you doing?
你能装  我就不能装了
You can have an accent, but I can't?
小伙子  早啊
Top of the morning to you, laddies.
别闹了
Would you just please stop?
是的
Yes.
这个季节的孟买   气候非常怡人
Bombay is very, very nice this time of year.
（中央咖啡厅）
帮我点个小煎饼
Hey, will you grab me a cruller?
坐下啦
Sit down.
拜托你去看医生  大哥  疝气手术
Will you go to the hospital? Dude, hernia operations cost, like...
应该很贵吧
...a lot probably, okay?
而且  它越来越黑  越来越痛
Besides, it's getting darker and more painful.
就表示在好转
That means it's healing.
我借你钱
Look, I will loan you the money.
赶快去医院  把它
Just go to the hospital and let's just get that thing...
塞回去
...pushed back in.
谢谢  但我要很久才能还你钱
Thank you, but it'd take me forever to pay you that money back.
我又不想惦记这件事
And I don't want that hanging over my head, okay?
而且  只要医保恢复
Besides, as soon as my insurance kicks in...
我就可以动各种免费手术
...I can get all the free operations I want.
我打算先去做眼睛的雷射激光手术
I think I'll probably start with that laser eye surgery.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
嘿  怎么了
Hey. What's going on?
乔伊的疝气很严重
Well, Joey's got a bad hernia...
不过动了个眼睛雷射手术就好了
...but it's nothing a little laser eye surgery won't fix.
真的   我跟你讲  把手压在这里
Look, I'm telling you, if I put my hand on my stomach right here...
就不痛了
...it doesn't hurt that bad. Ah.
搞不好你会死
Hey, maybe you'll die.
钱德   我怕了
Chandler, I'm scared.
我们可以一起走
No, we can go together.
但不要拖的太久
Just don't wait too long, though...
因为星期五之前我就会挂掉
...because I'm out of here sometime before Friday.
但是我不想死
But I don't want to die.
不  会很好玩的
No, no. It'll be fun.
我们可以回来   吓吓他们
We can come back and we can haunt these guys.
给我  不要   这是我的
Give me them. No, they are mine.
是你偷我的  你才偷我的
You stole them from me. You stole them from me.
拿来
Give me them.
要不要一人一个
You just wanna each take one?
很公平   反正也没用过
Yeah, that seems fair. We never use them.
听着  你们真的得帮我
Look, I really need some help, okay?
为什么   为什么我要说英国腔
Why? Why did I have to speak in a British accent?
我该怎么办
What do I do?
慢慢的把口音改掉
Well, why don't you phase it out? Yeah, phase the accent out.
别人会以为你在适应美国生活
People will think that you're adjusting to life in America.
是啊  根本不会有人注意
Yeah, I mean, come on. No one will even notice.
搞不好根本没人在听
I mean, they're probably not even listening to you.
没人在听我讲话
They're not listening to me?
当然有在听你讲话
Of course they're listening to you.
每个人都在听你讲话
Everybody listens to you.
莫妮卡  你真的觉得我该慢慢改吗
Monica, do you really think I should try this phasing-out thing?
我觉得你很帅啊
I think you look fine.
好了  开始了  好
Whenever you're ready. Okay.
提米
Hey, Timmy.
我要给你一个
I've got a surprise...
惊喜
...for you.
停   抱歉
Hold it. I'm sorry.
这个惊喜是一组新秋千  别演得这么凝重
The surprise is a new swing set. If you could play it less intense.
好的   没问题   等我一下
Oh, yeah. Sure, no problem. Just hold on one second.
嘿  提米
Hey, Timmy.
我要给你一个惊喜
I've got a surprise for you.
天哪
Oh, my God!
所以我都喂我的狗吃跑路
So that's why I feed my dog Purina One.
今天就去搬一包吧
Pick up a bag today.
这时候你要把它搬起来  没错
That's where you pick up the bag. Exactly.
不是  台词是"搬一包"   所以你得把它搬起来
No, the line is, "Pick up a bag," so you need to pick up the bag.
或是用指的
Or I could just point to it. Huh?
跑路   跑路  今天就去指一包吧
Blah, blah, blah. Purina One. Point to a bag today.
我没过   对吧  没有
I didn't get it, did I? No.
好
Yeah, okay.
你好
Hi.
我是乔伊崔比亚尼
I'm Joey Tribbiani.
我来应征  "人"
I'm hereto audition for "Man."
"垂死的人" 吗
You mean "Dying Man."
没错
Yes.
快啊   再打一次   真的要打  好
Okay, come on. Do it one more time. Really? Really? Okay.
罗斯  你好  我是麦尼利博士
Ross, this is Dr. McNeely...
来自假口音大学的
...from Fake Accent University.
我们想聘你来当专职教授
We'd like you to come on board with us full-time.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
听我说
Listen to this.
预言错了   我不会死了
My reading was wrong. I'm not going to die.
真的  你怎么知道   因为我的预言巫师死了
Really? How do you know? Because my psychic is dead.
她一定是看错牌了  我很遗憾
She must have read the cards wrong. Oh, I'm sorry.
总比我死好
Ah, better her than me.
嘿  我们来烤饼干吧
Hey, let's bake cookies!
（银杯片厂）
恭喜你拿到这个角色  谢谢
Listen, I'm really glad you got the part.
你真的能演吗  能
Are you sure you can do this? Yeah.
谢谢你陪我来
And, hey, thanks for coming with me.
还有谢谢你帮我洗澡
And thanks again for helping me take a shower.
这样叫 "绝口不提"吗
Now, is that "never talking about it again"?
乔伊   都准备好了
Hey, Joey. We're ready for you.
这是亚历   他演你的儿子
Joey, this is Alex. He's gonna be playing your son.
你好  亚历
Hi, Alex.
我的手可没塞在裤子里
And, uh, as you can see, my hands are not in my pants.
好
0Kay.
亚历  当乔伊一说到
All right, uh, Alex. Now, when Joey says his line:
"好好照顾你妈"   你就要哭  懂吗
"Take good care of your mama, son," that's your cue to cry. Got it?
好的   来吧
All right, let's do this.
第五场   拍第一次
Scene five, take one.
开始
And action.
儿子  好好照顾你妈
Take good care of your mama, son.
拜托啦  儿子
Come on, son.
你妈是个好人
Your mama's good people.
停
Cut.
亚历  记住  这里应该要哭
Alex, remember, you're supposed to cry.
你这次可以哭吗  好吧
Can you cry for us this time? Okay.
好  重来
All right. From the top.
第五场  拍第二次
Scene five, take two.
拍第三十六次要来了
Take 36 is up.
再来一次
Let's try this again.
乔伊   你好了吗
You ready, Joe?
请问一下  你喊"开始"前
Uh, one thing, is it all right with you if I scream...
我可以大叫吗
...right up until you say, "Action"?
可以  好
Sure. Okay.
开始  儿子   好好照顾你妈
Action! Take good care of your mama, son.
卡
Cut. Aah!
抱歉  乔伊  你把衣服掀开来
I'm sorry. Hey, hey. Joe, why don't you lift up your shirt?
小鬼你看这里
Take a look at this, kiddo.
有个小孩哭了  摄影机  快拍
We have a crying child! Roll the damn cameras!
喂   罗斯在吗
Hello. Hello, is Ross there?
他不在   你要留言吗
No, he's not. Can I take a message?
好   我是罗斯的离婚律师
Yes, this is Russell, Ross' divorce lawyer.
我一直没有他的回音
Just tell him that since I haven't heard from him...
他应该是想试着经营这段婚姻
...I assume he's decided to give the marriage a try.
罗斯又结婚了  不会吧
Ross got married again? Aah! No.
好吧   继续   慢慢改掉口音
All right, keep going. We are phasing the accent out.
改掉口音
Phasing it out.
要不是进实验室重新化验结果
"So without retesting their results in the laboratory...
研究小组也不会发现
...the team would never haveidenfified".
原先的碳14定年结果有误
...the initial errors in their carbon dating analysis."
到这里有问题吗
Were there any questions at this point?
请说  你的口音怎么没了
Yes. What's happening to your accent?
再说一次  你说什么
Come again? What's this nonsense?
好吧   我不是英国人
All right. I'm not English.
我是长岛人
I'm from Long Island.
我一紧张  就会冒出
I was really nervous, and the accent...
那个腔调了
...just, um-Just came out.
很抱歉
Ha, ha. I'm sorry.
回到课堂上来
So if we could just get back to the lecture.
有任何问题吗
Um, were there any questions?
古生物学的问题
About paleontology?
我只是想留下良好的第一印象
All right, look, I was just trying to make a good first impression.
很显然  我搞砸了
Obviously, I screwed up.
但你们对我的看法很重要
But what you guys think of me is really important...
因为我想成为专职教授
...because I'm hoping to get a permanent job here.
如果你们愿意再给我一次机会  制造好感
So if you'd just give me another chance to make a good impression--
罗斯  你疯了吗
Ross. Are you crazy?
我还是你的老婆  你想瞒我一辈子吗
I am still your wife? What, were you just never gonna tell me?
你是哪里有病
What the hell is wrong with you?
我真想宰了你
Ugh, I could just kill you!
瑞秋  你好
Well, hello, Rachel.
你真的玩过了  真的
You've really done this before? Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
你就用力打下去  用力  好
You just take a big, big swing, okay?
不要手软
Now, don't hold back.
嘿   嘿
Hey. Hey.
你们在干嘛
What are you doing?
庆祝乔伊的医保恢复了
We're just celebrating that Joey got his health insurance back.
好
Oh, all right.